Luis Sánchez

Software Engineer

Profile

Creative Senior Software Engineer offering 8+ years of experience successful completing simultaneous projects. Enthusiastic about developing forward-thinking solutions to tomorrow's productivity problems. Resourceful and adaptable approach to challenges. Decisive leader and reliable team builder with results-focused and driven approach.

Employment History

Software Engineer (Sr) at In Motion, Santiago, Chile

April 2012 — Present

- Extensive use of .NET 4.7, .Net Core, MVC, Entity Framework 6 and Core, ASP.NET Identity, Identity Server, Web API 2, Web API Code.
- Lead small projects from start to finish with at least two (2) developers in the team using agile methodologies.
- Use of Microservices architecture.
- API V3 Google Maps.
- Use of CSS3, HTML5, Bootstrap and JavaScript to update legacy sites.
- Use of Docker using Azure DevOps Containers with CI and CD.
- TDD, Unit tests with NUnit and FluentAssertions.

Freelancer

September 2016 — Present

- Small web applications using the MERN Stack.
- Use of Python with Django to develop simple / informational web applications.
- Xamarin app for Android devices.
- Use of free cloud platforms like Heroku with Postgres Database; Atlas Mongo DB Clusters; Azure with Key Vaults, App Services, SQL Server and Docker Containers.
- Use of GitHub with CI. Images are created on Docker Hub with every push on the repository.
- Use of GitLab for sandbox projects.
- NodeJS with Express using MongoDB. Mocha / Chai / Supertest.

Education

Bachelor's Degree in Informatics Engineering, Universidad Católica Andrés Bello, Caracas, Venezuela

October 2009 — September 2003

High School Diploma, U.E. Santa Elena, Caracas, Venezuela

September 1998 — July 2003

Courses

ScrumManager, Expert level, ScrumManager.org. ID 13636

June 2015 — June 2015

TS: Microsoft .NET Framework - Application Development Foundation. Microsoft License 9023486, Microsoft

March 2012 — March 2012

Details

Simón Bolívar 2580, Santiago, 7750000, Chile +56 9 6432 9625 luis.sanchezm86@gmail.com

Links

Twitter

LinkedIn

Stackoverflow

GitHub

Experimental website

Skills

.NET C#, EF, Web API, MVC

Python with Django

NodeJS with Express

CSS3, HTML, JavaScript

SQL & NoSQL

React

Microservices architecture

Docker

Azure platform

Google API and GCP

Languages

Spanish

English

Hobbies

Cooking, Running, Tennis, Bicycling, PC gaming.